(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-29T20:21:42.406113",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
明日オレん家来るってさ
You said you'd come over tomorrow...
君がいきなり言うからさ
...since you suddenly brought it up.
今日二人じゃないんすね？
Aren't there just two of us today?
二人？さっきのここでやった人たち
Two? The people who were just performing here.
心で君を抱きしめる
I hold you close in my heart.
Oh baby この場所で君と出会い
Oh baby, meeting you in this place.
Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live SHINIER / ARIAKE ARENA 2025.10.29 WED / 開演までしばらくお待ちください
[Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live "SHINIER" - Ariake Arena / October 29, 2025 / The concert will be starting soon.]
Attention ご来場のお客様へ / 演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援OKです
[Attention: Notice to Attendees / Please be aware of flashing lights / Cheering loudly is OK]
見える?この目の涙
Can you see these tears in my eyes?
命の色に滲んでいる
Blurring into the color of life.
何を残して与えた?
What did you leave behind and give?
問いかけて 壊れて
Asking, and breaking down.
青と赤と白混ざるこの世界の中で叫んでいる
Shouting in this world where blue, red, and white mix.
何を求めて歩いた?
What were you searching for as you walked?
追いかけて 疲れて
Chasing it, getting exhausted.
どのくらい異常?
Just how abnormal is this?
壊れているの? 壊れているよ
Are you breaking? I am breaking.
それでも息を...したい したい
Even so, I want to... breathe, I want to breathe.
君に見えているの?
Can you see it?
夢のように最後の言葉も詰まるよ
Like a dream, my final words choke up.
ERROR
遠い日のこと 淡い光が空に満ちている
On a distant day, a faint light fills the sky.
何を選んで並べた? 涙色 重ねて
What did I choose and line up? Overlapping tears.
浮かぶその身体 意識の中 溶けて 滲んでしまう
That floating body melts and blurs within consciousness.
何を見てきて比べた? 悲しくて 忘れて
What did I look at and compare? Sad, and forgotten.
どのくらい異常?
Just how abnormal is this?
歪んでいるの? 歪んでいるよ
Is it distorted? It is distorted.
それでも息を...したい したい
Even so, I want to... breathe, I want to breathe.
夢を見ているの?
Am I dreaming?
想う君に最後の言葉も詰まるよ
My final words choke up for you whom I miss.
ERROR
与えることも 失うことも 忘れることも できないの?
Can I not give, lose, or forget anything?
暴れ出す このエラー 殺して 笑う僕が またエラー
This error rages. I kill it, and smiling, I error again.
壊しているの? 壊して知るの?
Am I breaking it? Do I know by breaking it?
それでも涙...イタイ 痛い
Even so, the tears... hurt, they hurt.
君に届いたのか?
Did it reach you?
歌う声に最後の言葉並べても 重なる色 滲んで
Even lining up final words in my singing voice, colors blur.
ERROR
果たすことも失うことも忘れることもできないの
We can't fulfill it, nor lose it, nor even forget it...
果たせない 笑う僕が馬鹿みたいだ
I look like a fool, smiling when I can't fulfill it.
壊しているの？ 壊して知るの？
Are we breaking it? Are we learning by breaking it?
それでも 涙
Even so, tears...
出会いたい 壊したい
I want to meet you, I want to break it.
キミに届いたの？ 歌う声に最後の言葉並べても
Did it reach you? Even if I string together final words in my singing voice...
重なる日々に
Drowning in overlapping days,
沈んで 壊れているの？
Are you breaking down?
壊して知るの？ それでも
Do you know by breaking? Even so,
息をして 息をして
keep breathing, keep breathing.
キミに見えてたの？
Was it visible to you?
夢のように最後の言葉詰まるよ
Like a dream, my final words choke up.
かわいた 虚しさと
With a dry emptiness
小さな この空を
and this small sky,
描いていた
I was painting it.
彼方の色
The color of the distance,
手を伸ばすほどに
the more I reach out my hand,
痛みの
the pain...
僕たちは 何度も
We've done it over and over,
何度も 問い掛けて
questioning it repeatedly.
灯火は
The lamplight
毎回 照らすから
always illuminates us.
まだ 世界は
The world is still
ねじけたまま やがて消えていくの
twisted, and soon it will fade away.
壊してゆくの
It's breaking apart.
静かな 暗闇と 確かな
With quiet darkness and certainty,
感覚を キミの中の正義が
feeling the justice inside you
廃が零れ落ちたら
crumble into ashes.
すべて試されて 見えないの
Everything is put to the test, yet unseen.
抱いていたいモノ 何度も失って
What I want to hold, losing it again and again,
この日々が夢であるなら
if these days are a dream,
まだ心は目を閉じたまま
my heart still keeps its eyes closed
やがて消えて 崩れてゆくの
and before long, it fades and collapses away.
辞めてよ 揺れる感情を 押し殺して
Stop it, crushing down your swaying emotions.
僕たちは 誤謬の中で 何度も試されて
We are tested time and again amidst fallacies.
まだ 聖域や 愛とか 儚げの
Still, sanctuaries, love, and fleeting things—
この世界は目を閉じたまま
this world keeps its eyes closed
やがて消えて 崩れてゆくよ
and before long, it fades and collapses away.
風に吹かれて 誰も気付かぬよう
Blown by the wind, so no one notices,
区別がつかない モノクロの世界
in a monochrome world with no distinction.
揺るぎだして
It starts to shake...
見える? この目の涙
Can you see? These tears in my eyes
命の色に滲んでいる
Blurring with the colors of life
何を残して与えた?
What did you leave behind and give?
問いかけて
Asking...
壊れて
Breaking...
青と赤と白
Blue, red, and white
混ざるこの世界の中で
mixing within this world
叫んでいる
I'm crying out
何を求めて歩いた?
What were you looking for as you walked?
追いかけて 疲れて
Chasing, getting tired
どのくらい異常?
Just how abnormal is it?
壊れているの?
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
I am breaking down
それでも
Even so
息をしたい したい
I want to breathe, to breathe
君に見えているの?
Can you see it?
夢のように
Like a dream
最後の言葉も詰まるよ
Even my last words choke up
ERROR
遠い日のこと
From a distant day
優しい光が空に溢れている
A gentle light is flooding the sky
何を選んで並べた?
What did you choose and line up?
涙色 重ねて
Layering the color of tears
浮かるその
Floating
身体 意識の中
within body and consciousness
溶けて 滲んでしまう
melting and blurring away
何を見てきて 比べた?
What did you see and compare?
悲しくて 忘れて
Sad and forgotten
どのくらい異常?
Just how abnormal is it?
歪んでいるの?
Is it distorted?
歪んでいるよ
It is distorted
それでも
Even so
息をしたい したい
I want to breathe, to breathe
夢を見ているの
Am I dreaming?
想う君に
Thinking of you
最後の言葉も詰まるよ
Even my last words choke up
ERROR
与えることも
Even if I give
失うことも
Even if I lose
忘れることもできないの?
Can't I even forget?
暴れ出すこのエラー
This error is acting up
殺して笑う僕がまたエラー
I laugh as I kill, another error
壊しているの? 壊して知るの?
Am I breaking? Do I know by breaking?
それでも涙...イタイ 痛い
Even still, tears... hurt, hurt
君に届いたの?
Have I reached you?
歌う声に最後の言葉並べても
Even if I line up my last words in song
重ねた色
the overlapping colors
滲んで
are blurring
壊れているの?
Am I breaking down?
壊れているよ
I am breaking down
それでも息を
Even still, I want to...
...したい したい
...breathe, breathe
君に見えていたの?
Did you see me?
夢のように最後の言葉も詰まるよ
Like a dream, even my last words choke up
ERROR
みんなー！
Everyone!
こようび…お疲れ様です！
Saturday... Great job!
あ、こようびって返してくれるんだ(笑)
Oh, you're answering "Saturday" (laughs)
イェーイ！
Yay!
常闇トワ 2nd LIVE「SBPR」！
Tokoyami Towa 2nd LIVE "SBPR"!
いよいよ始まりましたーー！
It's finally started!
えー、ちょっとびっくりすると思うんですけども、最初に「ERROR」を歌わしていただきました！
Um, you might be a bit surprised, but we performed "-ERROR" first!
びっくりした人ーー！ (笑)
Who was surprised?! (laughs)
そうだよね、そうだよね、びっくりしますよね。
Right, right, you'd be surprised, right?
で、そのあとに「Twilight」と「Palette」を歌わしていただきました。
And after that, we sang "Twilight" and "Palette".
えー、やっぱね、「ERROR」を持ってきた理由なんですけれども、
Um, as for why we brought "-ERROR" first,
ま、あの、「ERROR」を聴いて、常闇トワとのことを知ってくれたみたいな子もやっぱり
well, I figured there are quite a few kids who heard "-ERROR" and got to know about Tokoyami Towa,
多いと思うんだよね。そ、多いから、なんかちょっとエモいの持っていこうかなみたいな
so, since there are many, I thought, maybe I should bring something a bit emotional,
感じ地で、そんな感じで、ころっと、さらっと決めちゃいました！
and with that feeling, I just casually and smoothly decided on it!
なんか、結構最初のほうに、こう、しっとりする曲を持ってきたのは結構挑戦的だったのかなと思うんですけども、どうでした？
I think bringing such a mellow song right at the beginning was quite a challenge, but how was it?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え、みんなTシャツ来てくれてるやん！
Huh, everyone's wearing T-shirts!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ペンライトはね、あの、ドッキリにもなりかねないので気をつけてください！(笑)
And please be careful with your penlights, so it doesn't turn into a prank! (laughs)
あ、いいけどちょっとあの、尖りすぎたっていう
"Ah, it's fine, but it got a bit too edgy..."
ま、そ、それもありすけども、あ、思い出として残しといてください。
Well, that's part of it too, but please keep it as a memory.
はい！
Yes!
え、そしてね、今回
And now, for today's
え、ライブなんですけれども
live performance...
セカンドアルバムが、え、「Shin」というアルバムになっておりまして、
My second album is titled "Shin,"
ま、ライブもね、その「Shin」に沿って、え、「Shyena」というふうにつけさせていただいております。
and the live is named "Shyena" to match "Shin."
いただいてます！
I hope you enjoy it!
あの、歌はいいけど、
I can sing, but my talking is...
喋りが下手っていう、致命的に下手なんだけど、大丈夫そうか？
seriously terrible at speaking. Will I be okay?
あ、ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much! Thank you!
え、このね、「Shyena」はね、え、光るとか、輝くっていう意味があるので、
"Shyena" means to shine or to glow,
今日ね、ライブは来てくれてるみんなの心を輝かせるようなライブにしていきたいと思っています！
so I want today's live to make everyone's hearts shine brightly!
え、セカンドアルバムのね、楽曲もいっぱいあるので、お楽しみにしていてください。
There are lots of songs from the second album, so please look forward to them!
え、ありがと！
Thank you!
アルバムも買ってくれましたか？
Did you buy the album too?
嬉しいです。なんか、今日も
I'm so happy. You know, today too...
ちょっと、ライブ前に、あの、エゴサをしてたんですけども、
Right before the live, I was searching myself online...
あの、いっぱい現地でも買いましたみたいなポスカ、ポストカードをゲットしましたみたいな感じで、
and seeing tweets like "I bought lots of postcards at the venue!"
ツイートしてるのをみて、あ、ポストしてるのをみて、すごく嬉しかったです。
or "I got the postcards," made me so happy.
まだ慣れないんだよね、うん。
I'm still not used to it, yeah.
え、そして、え、今日なんですけれども、
And also, for today,
ファーストと一緒に、生バンドでやってやります！
just like the first one, we're doing it with a live band!
え、今日しか、なんと今日しか聴けないライブアレンジが、
With special live arrangements you can only hear today...
あるので、楽しんで、盛り上がってくれたら嬉しいです！
I hope you'll enjoy it and get hyped with me!
そして、え、今日は現地だけじゃなくて、配信もしております！
And today, besides being here live, we're also streaming!
なんと、ここらへんに手を振ると、可愛いトワちゃんが、あの、インターネッ...
Apparently, if you wave your hand right around here, cute Towa-chan will... on the intern...
なんかいろんなとこにアピールしながらやっていこうかなと思っております。
So I want to appeal to all kinds of places while performing.
え、そして今回の、え、ハッシュタグなんですけれども、ライブの感想のハッシュタグ、
And for today's hashtag for your live impressions...
＃シャープとわえみとはセカンドでたくさんポストしてください！
please post lots using "#TowaEmiTowaSecond"!
スクショオッケーていうことなので、いっぱい、あの、ちょっと、あの、漏れてる感じなので、
Screenshots are okay, so since there are lots of, you know, slightly leaked moments...
お願いいたします。スクショして、あの投稿する場合いは。はい、お願いいたします。
please do. If you post screenshots, I'd appreciate it.
そしてなんと、あ、これいつもの中継だから分かっちゃうかもしれないけど、え、そうなんです。
And surprisingly—well, since this is our usual stream, you might already know—yes, that's right.
YouTubeとTikTokでご覧の方は、あ、ここまでとなっております。すみません！
For those watching on YouTube and TikTok, our broadcast ends here. Sorry!
ええ、お前らのえじゃないだろ！いるだろ！何がえなんだよ。何に対するえなんだよ。
Hey, don't say "Eh?!" You guys are here, right?! What's with the "Eh?!" What are you even reacting to?
ねえ、あの配信の見てくれてる人とかが、「えー」っていう、あ、代弁してくれたってことね？
You mean the people watching the stream went "Eh~", voicing it out for them?
そうだよね、そうだよね。はい、ありがとうございます。
That's right, isn't it? Yeah. Thank you!
はい、なのでね、え、まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは、概要欄から配信サイトチェックして購入してくださいね！
So everyone who wants to keep getting hyped together, please check the stream link in the description and buy a ticket!
え、まずちょっとアンケートを取りたいと思います。
First, I'd like to take a little survey.
本日、え、東京から来たよって方ー！...半分ぐらいかな？半分ぐらい。
Raise your hand if you came from Tokyo today! ...About half, huh? Around half.
えー、じゃあ東京じゃないとこから来た人はー！
Ee, then how about people who came from outside Tokyo?!
めちゃくちゃ多いやん！めちゃありがとやん！
There are so many of you! Thank you so much!
えー、じゃあ、じゃあ北海道から来た人ー！
Ee, then... how about people who came from Hokkaido?!
いるやん！まじかよ！ありがとう！
There are some! Seriously?! Thank you!
じゃあ沖縄から来たって人ー！
Then, anyone from Okinawa?!
お、いるいるいる！ありがとう、ありがとう！ありがとう！
Oh, there are some! Thank you, thank you! Thank you!
え、じゃあ、ちょっとあの、もっと拡大していいですか？
Ee, then, can we expand the scope a bit more?
えー、日本じゃないとこから来た人ー！
Ee, people who came from outside Japan?!
おいおいおい、めちゃめちゃいるじゃねえか！おお、すごいすごい！ありがとう！
Whoa, whoa, whoa, there are so many of you! Oh, amazing! Thank you!
え、じゃあ、さらにめちゃくちゃ絞って、え、飛行機を...
Ee, then, narrowing it down even more... taking a plane...
12時間以上乗ってきた人？
Anyone who traveled for over 12 hours?
え、いるやん
Oh, there are some.
すご…
Amazing...
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
ということで、なんか「わー」って今言えました？
So, were you able to say "Waa" just now?
まだでも足りないか？
Or is that still not enough?
じゃあ、とはかけ声しちゃおうかな
Then, I'll call out to you.
盛り上がれますか！
Can you get hyped?!
結構最初のさ、声出てりやん
Your voices were pretty loud at first.
なんか、何回かやろうかなって思ったけど結構声出てたけど
I thought about doing it a few times, and your voices were already quite loud, but—
ちょもう一回ていうかじゃあ、
let's do it one more time.
盛り上がれますか！
Can you get hyped?!
じゃあ、次の曲いくぞー！ りーん！
Then, let's go to the next song! Rin!
いくぞ有明ー！
Let's go, Ariake!
描いた未来の景色がここにある。
The landscape of the future I drew is here.
弱さも抱き締めていくから
I'll embrace my weaknesses too.
広がった翼が輝いていく
The wings I've spread are shining.
「飛び立て？私と」
"Can you take off? With me."
等身大の私を映していたい。ただ
I want to reflect the life-sized me. Just
望む瞬間衝動になってんだ。
It becomes an impulse at the moment I wish for.
「くだらない」とか曇りきってる目をして
"It's trivial" I say, with clouded eyes,
可能性だって夢を見てみたいのに。
Even though I want to dream of possibilities.
ずっとわかっていたんだけど
I had always understood,
言葉は撃ってる対象に。
Words are the targets I'm shooting at.
「大袈裟だ」なんて思ってるんでしょ？
"It's exaggerated" you think, don't you?
ずっと黙ってたんだけど
I had always kept quiet,
心ってやっぱ正直だ。
My heart is honest after all.
撃ち込まれた「色」を感じて気がしている。
I feel like I've felt the color shot into me.
「ここだよ」響かせて
"I'm here," let it resonate.
掲げたこの腕わかんないんでしょう？
You don't understand these raised arms, do you?
明かりになっていく。
It becomes a light.
何回も盗まれて取り戻した
Stolen many times and taken back,
意志の傷跡に誓った。
I swore on the scars of my will.
失敗、後悔はない？
Failure, no regrets?
ため息の音がしている。
I can hear the sound of a sigh.
現状に不安はない？
No anxiety about the status quo?
飲み込んだ浸ってたんだ
I was swallowing it, immersed in it.
ああ忘れないように金輪際
Ah, so I won't forget, never again,
もう汚されないように。
So it won't be tainted anymore.
もっと笑っていたいんだもの
I want to laugh more.
大人になってく代償に。
As a price for becoming an adult.
あなただってきっと思ってるんでしょ？
You too must be thinking that, right?
ちゃんわかってたんだけど
I had properly understood,
心ってやっぱ正直だ。
My heart is honest after all.
消せなくなった「痛み」を感じて気がしている。
I feel like I've felt the pain that I can no longer erase.
照らしされたこの場所で
In this place that was illuminated,
咲かせた手ほね。わかんないんでしょう？
Look, the hand that bloomed. You don't understand, do you?
止まない私を待っている。
It's waiting for the unstoppable me.
何回も奪われて取り戻した
Stolen many times and taken back,
日々の傷口に誓った。
I swore on the scars of the days.
「ここだよ」響かせて
"I'm here," let it resonate.
「心」を響かせてずっと
Let the "heart" resonate, always.
「ここだよ」響かせて
"I'm here," let it resonate.
掲げたこの腕わかんないんでしょう？
You don't understand these raised arms, do you?
揺るぎない私になっていく。
I'm becoming an unshakeable me.
何回も盗まれて取り戻した
Stolen many times and taken back,
意志の傷跡に誓った。
I swore on the scars of my will.
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました。
The free part of the broadcast has ended. Thank you for watching.